<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[The Ramblin' Gambler]]></title>
  <link href="http://Gamble715.github.io/Ramblin-Gambler/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://Gamble715.github.io/Ramblin-Gambler/"/>
  <updated>2013-06-11T18:28:05+00:00</updated>
  <id>http://Gamble715.github.io/Ramblin-Gambler/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Daniel Gamble McAdam]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Context as a Constant]]></title>
    <link href="http://Gamble715.github.io/Ramblin-Gambler/blog/2013/06/10/context-as-a-constant/"/>
    <updated>2013-06-10T20:29:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://Gamble715.github.io/Ramblin-Gambler/blog/2013/06/10/context-as-a-constant</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<blockquote><p>“The best way to predict your future is to create it” <br/>― Abraham Lincoln</p></blockquote>


<p>In 2013, humanity sits on the cliff of the future. Technological and cultural innovation is becoming so rapid that we
are aproaching a time when it exceeds our very imaginations.<!-- more --> According to futurists such as
<a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ray_Kurzweil">Ray Kurzweil</a>, the technological acceleration represents the coming singularity,
an inevitable point at which computers will help us become more than normal humans. They will help us cure diseases, explore
space and revive the environment. With this newfound power to leverage technology in helping us solve these big problems
comes the resopsibility to know its limits and the potential danger it poses to our modern society. To guage where the
future may take us it helps to know where innovation has taken us thus far through the problems of Ancient Greeks to the
great inventions of the Renaissance and The Great Enlightenment.</p>

<p>Early on in the golden ages of Greek rule, the problems humans faced were fairly straightforward. We solved the basic
need of food and water by constructing granaries and harnessing the rivers and lakes that surrounded the cities. When our
minds turned from survival, intellectuals such as Archemedes, Plato and Aristotle championed the need to understand the
individual and his or her place in society. Western thought built its foundation upon these thinkers and ideas such as reason,
metaphysics, science, the republic, and skepticism came to life in the following centuries. The most important aspect of
these ideas is that they will be scrutinized, championed, and refined but always have their roots in humankind&rsquo;s earliest
inovative thinkers. They are constant inquireies throughout a variable history.</p>

<p>As the centuries passed many eastern philosophers, mathmaticians, and scientists read the translated works of these great
thinkers, and produced <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Science_in_the_medieval_Islamic_world#Domains_of_thought_and_culture_in_the_High_Caliphate">innovations</a>
of their own in fields such as algebra, ethics, medicine and cosmology. Interestingly enough, if it werent for these thinkers
we may have lost the wisdom of the earlier ancient thinkers through the superstitious dogmas of the dark ages. This era gave
birth to the innovative explosion of the Renaissance. Again, the most notable thinkers built their big ideas on the shoulders
of earlier intellectuals. An embodiment of this time is Leonardo Da&#8217;Vinci. He assimilated loosley connected ideas to bring
life to his creations. He studied fluid dynamics to ensure the realism of the river he was painting, he dissected countless
bodies to understand the mechanics of the human body so he may more accurately design an apparatus for their use. He is
called a rennaisance man not merely because he knew a great deal about many different topics but more importantly he could
see how they fit together and explained eachother. Many men follow in this innovative tradition to this day, an important
example being Steve Jobs.</p>

<p>As the Renaissance evolved there was a rigid clash between the men of individualistic pursuits of innovation and governments&#8217;
orderly mandates of conformity. In time this divide would be cracked open by the thinkers of the enlightenment. They found
that much like Da&#8217;Vinci&rsquo;s methods, humans needed a base knowldedge of a wide range of topics before making progress in any
one. Again they built off of the thinkers before them and constucted new ideas in all forms of knowledge. The difference is
that because of the industrial revolution, these ideas could be magnified to help even the most uneducated layperson become
wealthy. Modern entrepreneurship was born and a mans destiny was finally in his hands. This fed the individualistic fire even
more and was realized in the founding of a country that would champion the individual and give him the freedom to seek his
own destiny, The United States of America.</p>

<p>As far as we have come from building our homes with hay and pitch we still have pressing problems that if left unchecked will
destroy us all the same. We have unprecedented ammounts of pollution, populations of people who are still helpless in the
face of their governments and cultures that indoctrinate the entilement of entertainment instead of opportunity. In order to
survive in the future we must use every tool at our disposal to combat the passive threats to our race&rsquo;s wellbeing. I am
learning to code because computers are seen as the paramount tool, and building this blog to comment on our progress in
scaling the cliff of the future.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
